codewithoutrules.com 2019-04-20

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit, subscribe to emails, or make a purchase from https://codewithoutrules.com (the “Site”).

## Personal Information We Collect

When you visit the Site, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically-collected information as “Device Information.”

We collect Device Information using the following technologies:

  * “Cookies” are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org.
  * “Log files” track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.

Additionally when you make a purchase or attempt to make a purchase through our reseller, they collect and share with us certain information from you, including your name, billing address, payment information (including credit card numbers, PayPal information, or other payment information), email address, and phone number. We refer to this information as “Order Information.”

If you subscribe to our email list, our email service provider records which emails you have opened, and which links you have clicked. We refer to this information as “Email Information.”

When we talk about “Personal Information” in this Privacy Policy, we are talking both about Device Information, Order Information, and Email Information.

## How Do We Use Your Personal Information?

Our reseller uses the Order Information that we collect generally to fulfill any orders placed through the Site (including processing your payment information, arranging for shipping, and providing you with invoices and/or order confirmations). Additionally, we use this Order Information to: Communicate with you; Screen our orders for potential risk or fraud; and When in line with the preferences you have shared with us, provide you with information or advertising relating to our products or services.

We use the Device Information that we collect to to improve and optimize our Site (for example, by generating analytics about how our customers browse and interact with the Site, and to assess the success of our marketing campaigns).

## Sharing Your Personal Information

We share your Personal Information with third party service providers to help us use your Personal Information, as described above:

  * We use FastSpring to power our online store–you can read more about how FastSpring uses your Order Information [here](http://fastspring.com/privacy/). 
  * We use ConvertKit to manage our emails. You can read more about how ConvertKit protects your information [here](https://convertkit.com/privacy/).
  * We also use Matomo analytics to help us understand how our readers and customers use the Site–you can read more about Matomo [here](https://matomo.org/privacy/).
  * We use Cloudflare to speed up delivery of pages. You can read more about how Cloudflare protects your information [here](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/).

Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

## Do Not Track

Please note that we do not alter our Site’s data collection and use practices when we see a Do Not Track signal from your browser because this is a static site, except for Matomo analytics which will be disabled. See third party services’ terms of service for their handling of Do Not Track.

## Your Rights

If you are a European resident, you have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to exercise this right, please contact us through the contact information below.

Additionally, if you are a European resident we note that we are processing your information in order to fulfill contracts we might have with you (for example if you make an order through the Site, or subscribe to an email newsletter), or otherwise to pursue our legitimate business interests listed above. Additionally, please note that your information will be transferred outside of Europe, including to Canada and the United States.

## Data Retention

When you place an order through the Site, we will maintain your Order Information for our records unless and until you ask us to delete this information.

## Minors

The Site is not intended for individuals under the age of 13.

## Changes

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.

## Contact

For more information about our privacy practices, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact me by e-mail at [itamar@codewithoutrules.com](mailto:itamar@codewithoutrules.com).
